If you're a leader, you lead the way.
如果你是个领导者 凡事就得带头
Not just on the easy ones.
不只是轻松的事
You take the tough ones, too.
还包括艰难的任务
A good leader has to understand...
好的领导者
...the people that are under him, understand their needs...
必须了解他的属下 必须了解他们的欲求
...their desires or how they think a little bit.
以及他们的想法
It seemed like he always made the right decisions along the way.
他似乎一路走来 总是做出正确的抉择
He was a real soldier.
他是个真正的军人
Like, some of the officers...
像其他的一些军官
...I don't think I'd follow them into water.
我想我不会听从他们的指挥
But he was one of the best.
但是 他是最棒的
He went right in there and he didn't know.
他不管情况如何马上投入
He never thought of not being first...
他从没想过要落人之后
...or sending somebody in his place.
或是找人替代
I don't know how he survived.
我不知道他怎么存活下来
But he did.
但他做到了
Lew?
路?
Wake up. They want us back at regiment.
醒醒! 他们要我们回团部
Come on, Nix, get up. Let's go.
快点 尼克 起床了! 我们走!
Come on, something's up. Strayer's orders.
快点 有事发生了 史崔尔的命令
Okay, I'll be right down.
你先走 我马上下来
- Let's go, come on, you got 10 minutes. - Go away.
- 快点 还有十分钟 - 别烦我~
Come on, big guy, let's go.
起来 大家伙! 咱们走!
- Leave me alone. - Okay.
- 别烦我~ - 好吧
- Come on. - Goddamn it.
- 走啦! - 可恶!
That's my own piss, for Christ's sake.
老天 这是我自己的尿
Son of a bitch.
王八蛋
We're the only unit in the group that's got the Germans on the German side of the Rhine.
我们是唯一在德国的莱茵河岸遭遇到德军的盟军部队
If we'd have taken Antwerp and I'm not saying that would be easy...
我不是说这很容易 但若老早攻下安特卫普
...we'd be over the river, well supplied, and have the Krauts on their heels.
我们早就渡过河 带着充足的补给打得德军乱窜
Now, if I can just get lke on the phone... Are you listening to me?
我只要能让艾森豪威尔听电话就好 你在听我说吗?
Hangin' on every word.
一字不漏
Hey, Moose, you too?
穆斯 你也来了?
Yeah, whatever's going on, Sink is not happy.
对 不管怎样 辛克的脸好臭
Nixon, Heyliger. Meet Col. Dobie, British 1st Airborne.
尼克森 海立格 见过英军第一空降师的都比中校
Capt. Nixon is our 2nd Battalion S-2. That's First Lt. Moose Heyliger.
尼克森上尉是第二营指挥官 这是穆斯海立格中尉
It appears the British lost 8,000 men when Market Garden fell on its ass...
英军在市场花园作战损失了8000名弟兄
...which is why Col. Dobie has been tasked with coordinating a rescue operation...
所以都比中校来此协调救援行动
...for the Red Devils trapped when Arnhem fell.
救出安恒沦陷时被困的红魔鬼部队
Dutch resistance are harboring 140 of my chaps here just outside a Jerry-held town 15 miles north of the river.
荷兰抵抗组织在河北岸15里一座沦陷城镇外收容了我们的140位弟兄
They'll go to the riverbank and gather in the woods tonight.
我们今晚将设法抵达河岸在此处森林里集合
Pick a team and get them back across the Rhine as fast as possible.
从Ｅ连选出一个小队 尽快带他们过莱茵河
140 men?
140位弟兄?
Canadian engineers have supplied six boats.
加拿大工兵提供了六艘船
The rendezvous point is isolated and landable.
集结点很独立 且能登陆
I swam it myself last night. At approximately 0030 hours...
我昨晚自己游过一遍 凌晨3时
...they will signal the "V" for victory with a handheld red torch.
他们会以红色火把做出"V"字的胜利信号
That would be a handheld red flashlight.
美国说法是红色手电筒
We'll call this Operation Pegasus.
我们叫这次行动"飞马作战"
Bob, your 2nd Battalion is on the spot. Get it Done.
鲍伯 你们第二营负责任务
Capt. Nixon, assist Col. Dobie in every way possible.
你尽力协助都比中校
If you need anything at all, you come to me.
如果有什么需要尽管找我
- I can hardly ask for more. - Capt. Winters.
- 我已经很满意了 - 温特斯上尉
You haven't endorsed the Market Garden after-action report...
我还没看到你在市场花园任务报告上的签名
...or the updated Battalion TO and E. Why is that?
也没有你最新的营编制表 这是怎么回事?
I'll have them at CP at 1300, sir.
我会在下午1点前交到指挥所
I want an inventory on any material the British 43rd left behind:
我还要一份英军43师留下来的物资清单
Rations, medical supplies, transport.
包括口粮 医疗补给 运输工具
- An inventory. Yes, sir. - Dick.
- 一份清单 是 长官 - 迪克
I'm still waiting to write citations on that 5 October operation.
我一直在等着写10月5日作战的褒扬令
- I need your report. - The report. Yes, sir.
- 我需要你的报告 - 报告 是 长官
- Light a fire under it, Dick. - Sir.
- 你要加把劲了 迪克 - 是的
Now, goddamn it, we asked for this yesterday...
我们昨天就要这个
...and here it is today, a day late and a dollar short.
结果今天才给我 整整迟一天
Enemy disposition and maps in the S-2. We should have a look at that.
情报单位的敌军部署及地图 我们该参考一下
You say there's about 100 of 'em?
你说那儿约有一百人?
This is it, boys.
就是这样 各位
Get across the river, across the field and over the dike.
他们得先渡河 穿过旷野和堤道
That's a lot of territory to cover. Where you want us to go?
可得越过一大片地区 你要我们去哪儿?
You, Hashey, you get the penthouse.
你吗 赫胥? 你上阁楼去
Thank you. We're up top.
谢谢你 我们上楼去
- How bad does it get? - You'll find out.
- 情况有多糟? - 你会知道的
- That's a lot of territory to cover. - A couple of regular GI Joe's?
- 要涵盖的区域还真广 - 就靠几个美国大兵 是吧?
You said it. Come on.
没错! 走吧!
New guys giving the replacements the what-for, and why-is.
新进弟兄在带补充兵熟悉环境
I swear one of them's never shaved.
我敢说他们有人还未成年呢
- Yeah, kids. - This is a hell of a dog, Tab.
- 对 是群孩子 - 这可是只了不起的狗 泰柏
Thank you, there you go.
谢谢你 这个给你
- What'd you call it, Tab? - Trigger.
- 你叫它什么 泰柏? - 扳机
That's good. I like that. Trigger.
很好 我喜欢 扳机
Got anything on this?
有什么动静吗?
- No, it's all quiet. - We've got penetration!
- 没有 都很安静! - 我们被渗透了!
- Alley's hurt, get the doc. - Get him on the table.
- 艾利受伤了 我们需要医生 - 把他抬到桌子上
Yeah, it's Alley.
艾利 是艾利
- All right, I got this. - Alley, you're gonna be okay.
- 好了 这个我来拿 - 艾利 你会没事的
- Boyle, get Doc Roe. - Where am I?
- 波勒 快去找罗医生来 - 我在哪里?
- Something happened - What happened? - Where was it?
- 发生了什么事? - 在哪?
Crossroads, where the road crosses the dike.
十字路口 马路跟堤道交汇处
They knew we was there because of your loud mouth.
要不是你的大嗓门 他们也不会发现
Joe, back off.
乔 别吵了
Lesniewski, send a runner for Lt. Welsh.
莱斯尼斯基 派传令找威尔旭中尉
- Assemble me a squad. - Yes, sir. 1st Squad, on your feet!
- 中尉 派个班给我 - 第一班 起立!
- Weapons and ammo only! - Give me room.
- 只带武器弹药! - 让我过
Let's move! Let's go!
快 我们走
Boyle, get the boots off, elevate the leg.
波勒 把他的鞋脱掉 把腿抬高
Liebgott, use the sulfur.
李高特! 用硫磺
Let's get this done quickly, we got to move.
好 赶紧把它搞定 我们必须快点
Not too much.
不用洒太多
Alley.
艾利 没事了
- MG-42? - Yeah.
- 是MG42机枪吗? - 对!
What the hell are they shootin' at?
他们在向谁射击?
- What's down that road? - Regimental headquarters.
- 马路那头有什么? - 团部指挥所
But that's three miles away. Why are they giving away their position?
但那是在三里之外 他们为何要自暴位置?
They ain't as smart as me and you?
因为他们没有你我聪明?
I'll check it out anyway. Hold here, wait for my signal.
我还是得去看一下 留在这等我信号
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Holding here, I'm waitin' for a signal.
在这里等 我在等信号
This is our fallback position, here.
这是我们撤退的位置
Mortars, deploy here. 1st Squad, on me.
迫击炮部署在这里 第一班 跟我来
Go.
走
Second on the right.
右边第二个
First on the right.
右边第一个
Third on the right. Nail the machine gun.
右边第三个 把机枪歼灭
Second on the left, first on the left.
左边第二个 左边第一个
Wait for my signal.
等我的信号
Prepare to fire.
准备开火
Two rounds, AG, quick.
两发点放 连放不修正
- Fall back! - Fire.
- 撤退! - 发射!
Fire.
发射
Higgins! Handful of Krauts, based on the dike, 12:00!
德军在堤道上 12点钟方向
- How many Krauts are left up there? - I don't know.
- 上面还有多少德军? - 我不知道
But we got seven in one blow.
我们一次就干掉七个
Bring on Boyle and Perconte, go!
快去找波勒和派康提来!
Come on, fall back.
快点 撤退!
Suppressing fire.
压制射击
Suppressing fire!
压制射击!
Hashey, Garcia, follow me.
哈许 贾西亚 跟我来
Harry, tell Peacock to bring up the balance of 1st Platoon on the double!
哈利 叫皮卡克把第一排剩下的弟兄带过来
And another machine-gun squad, over.
还有再带一个机枪班来 完毕
Dukeman!
杜克曼!
Go get that machine gun on the right flank, go!
去把右侧的机枪干掉 去!
Christenson!
克里斯登生!
Fuck, Dukeman's down.
杜克曼挂了
Sir, the balance of 1st Platoon are here.
长官 第一排剩余兄弟到了
Gordon and More brought another 30 cal.
戈登跟摩尔到了 另一挺30机枪
Sir.
长官
They're behind a solid roadway embankment.
他们在坚固的堤岸后方
We're in a ditch. They can outflank us along the dike...
我们则在壕沟 他们想通的话...
...and catch us out here as soon as they figure that out.
就可沿着堤道两侧夹击消灭我们
So, how many Krauts are we talking about?
我们要面对多少德军?
There's a ferry crossing here...
有艘运兵船通过这里
...so, it could be a whole battalion, as far as I know.
就我所知可能有一整营
Okay, what are your orders?
好 那你的指示呢?
We got no choice.
我们别无选择
Here it is. Talbert, you'll take ten men along the dike.
计划是这样的 泰柏特 你带十个人沿堤道走
Peacock, you'll take ten men along the left flank.
皮卡克 你带十个人沿左侧走
I'll take ten up the middle, so follow me.
我带十个攻中路 大家跟紧我
Questions? Go!
有问题吗? 去吧!
Enter.
进来
I don't know why I'm still doing this.
不知道为何我还改不过来
What, drinking?
是说喝酒吧?
No, hiding it in your footlocker.
不是 是把酒藏在你的置物柜
I'm a captain, for Christ's sake.
我都已经是上尉了耶
Why don't you...
那你何不...
Why don't you just give it up?
干脆改掉?
Drinking?
戒酒?
No, hiding it in my footlocker.
不 在我柜子藏酒的习惯
You're a captain, for Pete's sake.
你已经是上尉了耶
Maybe you're right and this is the perfect place to stop drinking.
也许你是对的 也许这是戒酒的最佳地点
Right here on the business end of the Allied advance.
就在盟军前锋的端点
Cheers.
敬你
Dick, you know, that's not literature. You just keep it simple.
迪克 那不是文学创作 简洁就好
Try writing it in the first person plural, you know.
试着用第一人称复数
- Say "we" a lot. - Thanks for the tip.
- 就是多用"我们" - 谢谢提示
Fix bayonets.
上刺刀
Go on the red smoke.
等红色烟雾信号
No, wait! Wait for the signal.
等一下 等信号
Jesus.
老天
Move on,brothers
弟兄们 上!
Come on, boys!
弟兄们 上!
Four.
四
Five.
五
Holy shit!
我的老天!
- It's a whole other company! - No shit!
- 又来了一整连! - 没错!
Fire, fire, fire.
开火 开火 开火!
Easy Beaver to Easy Minor. Reinforce Easy at phase one yellow.
Ｅ连Ｂ呼叫Ｅ连Ｍ 请求对黄一区火力支援
Plus one, strike three. Fire concentration Charlie.
加一百码 三群密集射击
Dropped 200, left 100.
再减两百码 向左一百码
Repeat, plus one, strike three.
重复 加一百码 三群密集射击
Fire concentration Charlie. Dropped 200, left 100.
集中火力 再减两百码 向左一百码
Krauts in the open, fire for effect, over.
德军在空旷地 有效攻击 完毕
Heraus, Hande hoch. Schnell, schnell!
不许动(德语)
- What's he saying? - He's telling me that they're Polish.
- 他说什么? - 他跟我说他们是波兰人
Don't you believe it. There ain't no Poles in the SS!
波兰人? 鬼才相信! 党卫军里是没有波兰人
Move!
快走!
Jesus Christ
天啊
Shit!
可恶!
Luz, send Lightning a contact report. Boyle!
鲁兹! 给炮指挥所攻击报告 波勒!
Get up where you can spot the fall of those rounds, go!
到上头可以看见弹着点的地方
Incoming rogues!
敌炮射击!
Easy Company, take cover!
Ｅ连 找掩体
- Boyle's hit! - Jesus Christ, they got me.
- 波勒中弹了! - 他们打中我了
Take cover, it's German artillery.
找掩体 这是德军炮火
Get Boyle, he's down, come on, help me.
去救波勒! 他中弹了 快点 帮我
Jesus, Captain, they're SS.
老天 上尉! 他们是党卫军
Joe?
乔?
- Joe, knock it off. - Damn it, what?
- 乔...别闹了! - 可恶 干嘛?
- You're bleeding. - It's nothing, Captain.
- 你在流血 - 没事 上尉
Take these prisoners back to Battalion CP.
你带这些俘虏回营指挥所
- Get yourself cleaned up. - Yes, sir.
- 给自己清洗包扎 - 是
Come on, Kraut boys.
来吧 德国鬼子
- Joe? - Yeah.
- 乔? - 什么事
- Drop your ammo. - What?
- 弹药缴出来 - 什么?
- Drop your ammo. - You kidding? What are you doing?
- 把枪给我 - 开玩笑? 你要干什么?
- Give me your weapon. - Captain.
- 把你的枪给我 - 上尉
You have one round. Johnny, how many prisoners do we have?
你只有一发...子弹! 强尼 我们有几个战俘?
We got eleven right now, sir. Okay.
现在有11个 长官
You drop a prisoner, the rest'll jump you.
你若射杀一个战俘 其他人会攻击你
I want all prisoners back at Battalion CP alive.
我要所有战俘活着押回营部
Yes, sir.
是 长官
"They got me." You believe that?
"他们打中我了" 你相信吗?
You believe I said that?
你相信我竟然这么说吗?
- Can you make it back to CP? - Yeah.
- 你能撑回营部吗? - 可以
All right, I will see you someplace else.
那就好 我们别处再碰头
Take these to Battalion.
把这些带回营部
- Split 'em up. - Yes, sir.
- 把他们分开 - 是
Up. All right.
抬起来! 很好
Here you are.
喝口水
We had 'em on the run.
我打得他们乱窜
How's that?
说说看
The Germans were flooding back towards the ferry crossing when we hit 'em with artillery.
我们炮击时德军刚好蜂拥回渡船口
It was like a turkey shoot.
就象是在打火鸡
Then they hit us with their 88s, zeroed in on this crossroad.
然后他们用88毫米炮反击 集中在这十字路口
Now we were lucky, though.
我们算是走运了
Only 22 wounded.
只有22个人受伤
Lucky?
运气好?
- Capt. Winters? - He's right down there, sir.
- 温特斯上尉呢? - 就在下面 长官
All right, carry on.
好 继续工作
All right, Krauts, Hande hoch.
好了 德国佬 手举起来
22 wounded? You okay?
22人受伤? 你还好吗?
- Yeah, one killed. - Who?
- 还好 有一人阵亡 - 谁?
Dukeman.
杜克曼
You're looking at two full companies of SS out there.
你们碰到的可是整整两连的党卫军
About 50 dead, probably another 100 wounded.
歼灭大约50人 可能100人受伤
Seven back in the regimental cage plus a whole string of 'em up there.
营部牢里有7个 再加上上头还有一整串
That's not bad for Dukeman.
对杜克曼而言不算太坏
You got a drink?
你有喝的吗?
Of water?
水?
Yeah, it's water.
对 这是水
Thanks.
谢了
Okay?
还好吗?
363rd Volksgrenadier hit Opheusden early this morning...
德军第363炮兵团在今早炮击欧福斯登
...about the same time your SS made a run for my CP down the road.
大约同时党卫军对我的指挥所发动攻击
3rd Battalion got the hell beat out of 'em.
第三营被他们重创
- Holly Horton was killed. - Maj. Horton's dead?
- 哈利贺顿阵亡了 - 贺顿少校死了?
They hit 2nd Battalion CP in force.
他们猛烈攻击第二营指挥部
He was organizing the defense.
他当时在进行防御工作
Capt. Nixon, excuse us for just a minute.
尼克森上尉 失陪一下
How'd you feel about handling the battalion?
你对管理营部有何想法?
Sir?
长官?
I'm moving you up to executive officer of 2nd Battalion.
我要升你做第二营主任参谋
Col. Strayer is... He could use some help.
史崔尔中校... 他需要帮手
- I know I could handle them in the field, sir. - That's right, Dick.
- 长官 我在战场上能带兵 - 没错 迪克
You're a solid tactician and a good leader. Don't worry about administration.
你是个战术家、好领袖! 不用担心行政的事
Who do you think'll be taking over Easy, sir?
你认为谁会来带领Ｅ连 长官?
Moose Heyliger can command Easy Company.
穆斯海立格将带领Ｅ连
Lt. Heyliger would be my choice, sir.
海力格中尉也会是我的选择
Good.
很好
You pack your gear and come to Battalion CP.
去收拾你的东西 到营指挥所去报到
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Would you like some coffee, sir?
要来杯咖啡吗 长官?
- Yeah, thanks, doc. - All right.
- 好的 谢谢你 医生 - 不客气!
Dick!
迪克!
Finish your novel yet? That's a lot of homework.
小说完成了吗? 好多家庭作业喔
And I thought executive officer was a fun job.
我以为参谋是个有趣的工作
- Who are you? - Zielinski, sir.
- 你是谁? - 奇林斯基 长官
- Who is he? - Zielinski, my orderly.
- 他是谁? - 奇林斯基是我的勤务兵
Rank does have its privileges.
当官的可真有特权
Orderly? I suppose you do stuff like get coffee.
勤务兵? 我猜你能做像倒咖啡之类的事?
- Can do, sir. - Black, no sugar.
- 我可以 长官! - 黑咖啡 不加糖
And a bacon sandwich. You want something?
还要培根三明治 你要什么吗?
Bacon sandwich.
培根三明治
You can give that to Col. Sink with my compliments.
把这拿给辛克上校 帮我谢谢他
All that for two pages.
搞了半天才写两页?
Guess that means that's gonna take a while.
我想要等它完成 还有得等了
Yeah, it is. You want a job?
是的 没错 你需要工作吗?
There. I think somebody wishes you were back in charge of Easy Company, Moose.
我想有人巴不得赶快回去指挥Ｅ连呢 穆斯
- Are you two just here to gloat? - No, just rub it in a little bit.
- 你俩是来幸灾乐祸的吗? - 不 只是来消遣你一下
Moose is gonna lead his first mission as CO.
穆斯马上要以连长的身份出第一个任务
Operation Pegasus is set to go off. I wanted to give you the heads up.
"飞马"作战即将展开 我想该跟你说明计划
Pegasus, yeah.
"飞马" 很好
Yeah, great.
很好 太好了
- Everybody know their job? - We've drilled with the boats all day.
- 大家都清楚任务? - 我们整天都带着小艇演习
Lt. Welsh is coming along, and the Canadian engineers.
威尔旭中尉和加拿大工兵都来了
Col. Dobie knows his stuff.
都比中校蛮有一套的
Know how many times you'll cross the river?
你们要渡河几次?
If there really are 140 Brits in hiding over there, 3 trips.
如果真躲着140个英军 3次
Speed is the key. What time's jump-off?
速度是关键 何时跃出?
We'll be at the far side of the Rhine at 0100.
我们会在凌晨1点到达莱茵河对岸
Speed is the key. Keep moving and lead the way.
速度是关键! 保持前进 引导部队
Dick.
迪克
Easy's in good hands.
Ｅ连会被好好照顾的
Yeah.
对
- Yeah, right. Well, hang tough. - I could say the same to you.
- 那么 好好干! - 你也一样
- Good luck, Moose. - Captain.
- 祝你好运 穆斯! - 上尉
- Nix? - Yeah.
- 尼克? - 嗯!
- Are we sure on the intelligence of this? - I think it's pretty good.
- 你确定这次的情报没问题吧? - 我想没有
Is Easy walking into another company of Germans no one can see?
Ｅ连会不会朝向躲着的德军连队前进?
Why don't we ask Moose when he gets back?
我们何不等穆斯回来时再问他?
Right, yeah.
是的
If they do run into any trouble, you'll let me know?
如果他们真的遇上麻烦 你会告诉我吧?
Yeah.
当然
You run into any bacon sandwich, do the same, all right?
若你看到培根三明治也要告诉我 好吗?
- Line secure, sir. - Fall back into position, Private.
- 防线安全了 长官! - 返回你的位置 二等兵
I got the 30 cal on the left flank.
我在左翼有一挺30机枪
Extend it out to the left, 10 yards.
再把它向左延伸十码
So, Colonel, where are they?
中校 他们在哪儿?
Leicester. Square.
莱瑟斯特
Come on in.
过来
- Welcome back, sir. - Good to be back.
- 欢迎回来 长官 - 回来真好
Heyliger, 506 of the 101st Airborne.
我是海立格 101空降师506团
Never thought I'd be so glad to see a bloody Yank.
从来没想到看到美国佬会这么高兴
- Your show, Colonel. - I'll be back shortly.
- 交给你了 中校! - 我马上就回来
Go.
走吧
- Boats are all secure, sir. - Bull.
- 螺栓都拴紧了 长官 - 大牛
The Brits are on the way, pass the word.
跟大家说英国人上路了
Sir, you missed a signature here.
长官 您这儿漏签了字
- Moose Heyliger? - That's me, sir.
- 穆斯海立格? - 是我 长官
God bless you, my man.
上帝保佑你
- We're ready to go, sir. - Where's the rest of you?
- 我们准备出发了 长官! - 其他人呢?
Right.
好的
- And here we all are. - Let's go.
- 我们都到了 - 走吧!
Wahai, Mohammed! Wahai, Mohammed!
杀 穆罕默德!
Moose Heyliger and the American 101st...
穆斯海立格和美国101空降师
...have done the Red Devils a great service, making it possible for us to return...
帮了红魔鬼英军第一空降师一个大忙! 让我们得以回来
...and fight the enemy on another day.
与敌人择日再战
To Easy Company, victory and Currahee.
敬Ｅ连 还有胜利和葛拉锡!
Currahee!
团结一致!
I was only Easy's CO for four months, Moose.
我当Ｅ连指挥官不过四个月
Before that it was Meehan's company, and before that Sobel's.
( 荷兰 德里尔 ) 前任连长是米汉 再之前是苏贝尔
But you're the only combat commander they've ever known.
对 但你是他们唯一认识的战斗指挥官
And I'm from another company.
而我是从别的连调来的
You know where they came from, you know what they've been through.
你知道他们打哪儿来的 你知道他们经历过什么事
Just hang tough.
只要坚持下去
Train your new platoon leaders, and trust your noncoms.
训练你的新排长 信赖你的班长
Halt!
站住!
- It's Moose. - Hold your fire!
- 我是穆斯... - 不要开枪!
Okay, buddy.
好的 兄弟
Oh, my god.
我的天
Send for Lt. Welsh.
快去找威尔旭中尉来
Stay awake on me, Moose.
你要保持清醒 穆斯!
Here, look in my eyes. Send for Lt. Welsh, now!
看着我立刻去找威尔旭中尉!
Okay.
没事的
I'm sorry, sir. I'm so sorry. I didn't know.
我很抱歉 长官 真抱歉 我不知道
Jesus Christ.
天啊
- Where are you from, trooper? - Wyoming, sir.
- 你是从哪里来的? - 怀俄明州 长官
You're a long way from home, Private.
你离家好远 阿兵哥
Stretcher! I got him, Harry.
担架! 我来抬!
- Give him morphine? - Yeah.
- 你给他打了吗啡? - 嗯!
- How much? - I don't know, two, three Syrettes maybe.
- 打了多少? - 不记得了 两三剂
- Three Syrettes maybe? - Yeah.
- 三剂? - 嗯!
- Were you trying to kill him? - I think it was two.
- 老天 你想害死他吗? - 好像是两针
It's important to let me know how much medication he's had.
重要的是我必须知道他已经被注射了多少剂量
I do not see one Syrette on the man's jacket.
我在他的夹克没找到注射器
- Sorry, doc. - Sure is a good thing he's a big man. Maybe he'll stand a chance.
- 我很抱歉 医生 - 还好他身材壮硕 或许还有机会
We didn't know what to do for his pain.
他刚才痛苦不堪 医生 我们不知道该怎么办
Yeah, but you are officers, you are grownups, you ought to know.
你们都是军官 成年人 你们应该知道
All right, let's go, come on, move it!
好了 我们走 快点 走了!
Mama, mama, can't you see
∮妈妈 妈妈 你知道吗∮ ( 1944年12月10日 法国 莫米昂李葛兰 )
What the airborne's done to me?
∮空降部队都对我干了些什么∮
- Once more. - About face.
- 再一遍 - 向后转
Forward march.
齐步走
Easy still has only 65 percent strength...
Ｅ连还是只有65%的战力
...and most of those are replacements, including their new CO.
大部分还是补充兵 包括他们的新连长
- How's Lt. Dike doing? - Three weeks in Holland...
- 戴克中尉现在如何? - 才到荷兰三个礼拜
...the guys are already calling him Foxhole Norman.
阿兵哥已经叫他散兵坑诺曼
They're talking about a mid-march action at the earliest.
他们说最早有可能在三月中进行的作战
So, we train the guys for three months, we jump into Berlin, we end the war.
所以...我们训练新兵三个月 跳伞到柏林 把战争结束
The only thing holding together Easy Company is the NCOs, Toccoa men.
唯一将Ｅ连维系在一起的是那些资深的士官们
Sir, there's a Sgt. Guarnere here to see you.
长官 有位葛奈瑞的士官要见您
Look what the train brought in.
看看火车带来些什么人
- The daredevil. - Hiya, Captain.
- 敢死队的! - 上尉 你好!
Welcome back, Bill.
欢迎回来 比尔
It's true. I never thought I'd see you behind a desk.
老天 是真的 我从来没想过你会坐办公桌
Yeah, and someday he'll sit behind it.
对 有天他还会更上层楼
I just went awol from the hospital to get back here, sir.
我刚才没有请假 离开营地 从医院来这
I hope it won't cause you a problem.
长官 希望不会对你造成麻烦
- Would you care if it did? - Not a bit, sir.
- 就算会 你在乎吗? - 一点也不 长官
Got a letter for you here from Moose, Lt. Heyliger, sir.
我带来封穆斯 海立格中尉的信
He's recovering, but it's gonna be a long haul.
他在复原中 但得花上段时间
Thanks, Bill.
谢谢你 比尔
I hear there's gonna be a football game. Those chumps from the 5-0-deuce, right?
听说要举办足球赛 有从502团来的大块头 是吗?
- Yeah, Christmas day. - Great, sky train boys.
- 没错! 是在圣诞节 - 真棒 空降部队锻炼人
Can't wait.
我等不及了
Great.
真棒
I
我...
- I'll just go find some trouble. - You do that.
- 要去找些麻烦了 - 你去吧
- Bill. - Sir?
- 比尔! - 长官?
No more joyriding, right?
别再兜风了 好吗?
Anybody ever heard of a little joint called Lulu's?
有人听过一间叫做..."露露"的酒馆吗?
You got me.
你难倒我了
I'll just ask around.
我四处问问好了
I guess now's as good a time as any.
我想现在是时候了
What's that? I don't wanna see another piece of paper.
那是什么? 一张纸? 我不想再看到任何纸
Gen. Taylor has flown back to Washington.
泰勒将军奉命飞回华盛顿
He's left Gen. McAuliffe in charge of the division.
留下麦考利夫将军指挥
Col. Sink is in Rheims to see Marlene Dietrich.
辛克上校去里姆斯见玛琳黛德丽
- Marlene Dietrich is in Rheims? - At the USO.
- 玛琳黛德丽在里姆斯? - 在劳军联合组织
I'm going to Rheims.
我要走了 我要去里姆斯
Strayer is in London for at least a week for Lt. Col. Dobie's wedding.
史崔尔参加都比中校的婚礼 至少还要在伦敦一礼拜
I am heading back to Aldbourne to look up a certain young lady.
我则回去爱德布恩找一位年轻的姑娘
- What are you telling me? - You, my friend, are headed to Paris.
- 你想告诉我什么? - 我的朋友 你要去巴黎
City of light. That's a 48-hour pass.
灯光之都 那是48小时外出假条
It's been decided that you need a little dose of civilization.
我们决定你需要一点文明的洗礼
Bon voyage.
旅途愉快(法语)
I second that.
我附议
The airborne is as tough as they come.
伞兵也一样的强悍
Basic training.
新兵训练
You know what I did in basic training?
你知道我在新兵训练做了什么?
I had to eat rats in basic training.
我得在新兵训练时吃老鼠
That's the first time...
那是我第一次
Monsieur?
先生? (法语)
Monsieur, c'est le terminus. Le train s'arrete ici, on doit tous descendre.
这是终点站了(法语)
Every time I look at you, I see eight or nine of you.
每回我看着你 我看到八个或九个你
- I'll be all right when I can only see one. - Look at me, I'm John Wayne.
- 当我只看到一个就没事了 - 看着我 我是约翰韦恩
The costume department set me up with these great navy whites.
戏服部门帮我弄到这些漂亮的海军制服
Luz, shut up.
鲁兹 闭嘴
What do you think?
你觉得如何?
- I'm trying to watch this. - I've seen this movie 13 times, okay?
- 我在看电影 - 我这部戏看过13遍了
- I haven't, so, shut up. - Watch the movie. It's fine.
- 我还没 所以闭嘴! - 好吧 你看
- Skip. - Come on.
- 史基普! - 拜托!
Where've you been? I've been lookin' all over for you.
你去哪里? 我到处找你
Don, I was at home in Tannawanda.
唐 我本来在老家
But then Hitler started this whole thing, so, now I'm here.
可是被希特勒一搞 我现在在这儿了
- How'd you make out in craps? - Not so bad.
- 你骰子赌得如何? - 还不错
- Here's the $60 I borrowed. - You're paying me back?
- 向你借的60块钱 - 你要还我钱?
- And, to say thank you... - Surprising.
- 还有 要谢谢你! - 令人惊讶!
- ...a tip. - Jesus!
- 小费! - 老天!
Shut up! Shut up!
闭嘴!
I was up $6,000, but I only have $3,600 left.
我本来最多赢了六千 可是我现在只剩三千六
What will you do with it?
你要怎么用这些钱?
Blow most of it in Paris as soon as possible.
尽快在巴黎花光
Gimme a tip.
分一点红给我
I don't think that climate in there agrees with you.
我不认为那里的气候适合你
As a matter of fact I've been worried about your health altogether.
事实上 我一直担心你的健康
- Hey, Buck. - You don't look well.
- 巴克! - 你看来不太舒服
How are you feeling? Your wounds heal, all four of them?
你觉得如何? 伤口愈合了吗? 四个都好了吗?
You seen this before?
你以前看过这电影吗?
Buck.
巴克!
- Hi. - Is it any good?
- 嗨~ - 好看吗?
Yeah.
很好
- It's a real corker. - I warned you about this girl a month ago.
- 真是太棒了 - 我一个月前就警告你要小心这姑娘
Won't anybody give you a light?
没有人帮你点火吗?
Lip, favorite part.
李普 我最喜欢的一段
- "Got a penny? - Got a penny?"
- 有一便士吗? - 有一便士吗?
- What? - It's an English penny...
- 怎样? - 有的 这是英国一便士
Lights!
开灯!
- Come on. - Quiet!
- 拜托~ - 安静!
You can't do that to the Duke.
你在干嘛 你不可以对我们这样
I said, quiet!
我叫你们安静
Elements of the 1st and the 6th SS Panzer Division...
德军党卫军第一装甲师及党卫军第六师装甲师
...have broken through in the Ardennes forest.
已经突破阿登森林
They've overrun the 28th Infantry and elements of the 4th.
他们现在已经击溃第28步兵师及第4师
All officers report to respective HQs. All passes are cancelled.
所有军官立刻向所属指挥部报到 休假取消!
Enlisted men report to barracks and your platoon leaders.
征召兵向营区所属排长报到
Damn, what a day.
可恶 真是多事的一天
Got a light?
有火吗?
- Sir? - Lt. Peacock?
- 长官? - 皮卡克中尉?
- Sir, have you seen Col. Strayer? - Where's the company commander?
- 请问有看到史崔尔中校吗? - 你们连长到哪儿去了?
Lt. Dike, I've been looking for him all day.
戴克中尉吗? 我整天都在找他
How is it that the 4th Army's problem gets dumped on the airborne?
陆军第四师的麻烦怎么会丢给空降部队?
Lt. Peacock, Lt. Compton, Capt. Winters.
皮卡克中尉! 康普顿中尉! 温特斯上尉!
- Lt. Dike, I've been looking for you. - We have a problem.
- 戴克中尉 我一直在找你 - 长官 麻烦了
Col. Strayer is not back from some wedding in London. Can you believe that?
史崔尔中校去伦敦参加婚礼还没回来 你相信吗?
We're going to the front here and our CO isn't even in the same country.
我们都要上前线了 而指挥官甚至都不在同一个国家
You have a bigger problem. Lt. Dike
戴克中尉 有个很严重的问题
Men are returning to action without proper cold weather clothing or enough ammo.
你们的弟兄将会缺乏足够的冬装和弹药回到战场
Sir?
长官?
I suggest you take a canvass of the entire base.
我建议你到整个基地尽量找
Get what materials you have before you roll out.
尽可能在出发前将物资凑齐
- Or have you done that already? - No, sir.
- 或许你已经在做了? - 还没 长官
K-rations, as many as you can scrounge.
尽量做到Ｋ级补给
- We don't know if we'll be resupplied. - Yes, sir.
- 我们不知何时才会再补给 - 是的 长官!
- What about ammo? - There is no more ammo.
- 弹药怎么办? - 没有多余的弹药了
Distribute it as best you can so at least everybody has something.
尽可能在弟兄间平均分配 让每人至少都有一点
Yes, sir.
是的 长官!
Lt. Compton, Lt. Peacock, inform Lt. Shames of the situation.
康普顿中尉 皮卡克中尉 告知宣姆士中尉这情况
Equip your platoons as best you can...
将你们的排尽可能的补齐装备
...and then report to me, understood?
然后回来向我报告 懂吗?
- Yes, sir. - Captain.
- 是 长官! - 上尉!
I guess the blackout's not in effect. Luftwaffe must be asleep.
我猜并没有实施灯火管制 德国空军一定在睡觉
What a difference a day makes, Lieutenant.
这一天内的变化真大 对不对 中尉?
Christ, I miss those C-47s.
老天 我真想念那些C47
We've got a tailgate jump here.
我们要从这群卡车里跳伞
Where are they sending us? What are we supposed to do with no ammo?
我只想知道要送我们去哪 还有没弹药怎么办?
Kid, what's your name again?
小子! 再说一次你的名字
Suerth. Suerth, Junior.
索斯 索斯二世
- You got any ammo, Junior? - Just what I'm carrying.
- 你有弹药吗 索斯? - 只有身上带的
What about socks, Junior? You got extra socks?
那袜子呢? 你有多的袜子吗?
- A pair. - You need four, minimum.
- 一双! - 你最少需要四双
Feet, hands, neck, balls. Extra socks warms them all.
双脚 双手 脖子 蛋蛋 多出来的袜子让他们都保暖
Okay, we all remember that one. But did we remember the socks?
好 都记得这一点 但我们有多带袜子吗?
I'd give my goddamn boots for a cigarette.
没错 我愿意用我的靴子来换一包烟
- We're out of ammo and socks. - Anybody got a cigarette?
- 我们没弹药也没袜子 - 有人有烟吗?
- I bet Junior's got plenty of both. - I don't.
- 我打赌二世一定两样都有很多 - 我没有
- How about a hat, you got a hat? - You got extra ammo?
- 那帽子呢? 你有帽子吗? - 你有多余的弹药吗?
- What about a coat, you got a coat? - I need to pee.
- 那外套呢? 你有外套吗? - 我要小便
How about some smokes then?
那烟呢?
- Yeah, I got some smokes. - Now you're talking.
- 有 我有些烟 - 你总算说人话了
- Over here. Pass them down. - Somebody, give me a light.
- 丢上来 传过来 - 谁借我个火
Keep moving. Come on, keep it coming.
继续前进 向前走
Over to the left.
转到左边来
Keep it moving. All the way down.
继续开过来 一直走过去
Get moving, guys.
下车 伙计们
All right guys, 15 minutes. Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
好了 你们有15分钟 拿到烟的赶快抽
- Keep warm, guys. - Where the hell are we?
- 大家注意保暖 - 我们到底在哪里?
Sure we ain't in hell, it's too damn cold.
肯定不是在地狱 这里太冷了
Stand back, guys. I've been holding this for the last hour.
你们退后点 我已经憋了一小时
Anybody got any matches?
有火柴吗?
Gather round, guys.
这样好多了 靠过来 大家围过来
Wait right here, don't go anywhere. Welcome to Belgium.
就停在这儿 别去任何地方 欢迎来到比利时
This area's known as Bastogne.
这里叫巴斯通
Strategic crossroads town.
是战略要道
Seven roads leading in, seven roads leading out...
七条道路进 七条道路出
...which makes it ideal for Kraut armor.
很适合德军装甲部队行动
Now, lke wants to make sure...
艾克要让...
...that the Krauts can't use those roads...
德军无法使用这些道路
...so, we'll put a perimeter around Bastogne...
所以我们将在巴斯通周围设阵地、挖战壕
...dig in tight as a tick.
象虱子一样深深粘着
- 2nd Battalion will deploy to the east in this wooded area. - Thank God...
- 第二营将部署在东边的森林区 - 感谢老天!
- ...barely made it. - Better get yourself some ODS, Bob.
- 差点没赶上 - 去找你的值星官 鲍伯
Okay.
好的
1st Battalion's to the north on your left flank.
第一营在北作为你的左翼
3rd Battalion's in reserve. Andy, let's roll.
第三营为预备队
- Sir, we're a little short on ammunition. - How short?
- 长官 我们缺少弹药 - 差多少?
There was a limited supply in camp, sir.
营区都限额补给 长官
Captain, you beg, borrow, or steal ammo, but you defend this area.
上尉 我不管你去求 去借 或偷 都得守好这
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Jesus Christ.
我的老天
Bill, Don, come here, look at this.
比尔 唐 过来 看看这个...
Hold on. Jesus, I'm done.
拜托 老天 我尿完了
What the...
搞什么
What the hell is going on?
到底发生了什么事?
You're going the wrong way.
你们走错方向了
Pal.
朋友
Pal, what happened? Where the hell are you going?
发生什么了? 你们要去哪里?
They came out of nowhere, they slaughtered us.
他们突然冒出来屠杀我们
- You gotta get outta here. - We just got here. - Give me your ammo.
- 你们得离开这 - 我们才刚到 - 把你的弹药给我
- Come on. - Take it, you'll need it.
- 快点! - 拿去! 你会用的上的
Go on, get out of here.
走吧 离开这里
Jesus Christ
我的老天
- Who's got ammo? - You got ammo?
- 过来 谁有弹药? - 你有弹药吗?
- Gimme your ammo. - Who's got ammo?
- 给我你的弹药 - 谁有弹药?
- You got any grenades? - Come on, hand 'em over.
- 你有弹药吗? - 快 拿过来
- Gimme it. - You got grenades?
- 拿过来 - 你有手榴弹吗?
- Got any grenades, Lieb? - Who's got grenades?
- 李 你有手榴弹吗? - 谁有手榴弹?
Private, what have you got?
阿兵哥 你有什么?
Make a hole!
让一让!
Make a hole! Make a hole.
让一让! 嘿~ 让一让!
I got ammo, grab what you can.
我拿到弹药了 能拿多少就来拿
Lieutenant, you're a godsend.
中尉 你真是上天恩赐
- What's the situation? - I heard you guys were coming in.
- 情况怎么样? - 我听说你们要来
There was an ammo dump, so here.
那里有个弹药堆积场 所以我就...
Is it just you guys in the 101st?
只有你们101空降师吗?
Looks like. What hit you fellows?
看来是这样 你们遭到什么攻击?
Everything.
什么都有
The Krauts had tigers, panthers, SPs, stukers...
德军有虎式坦克、豹式坦克、自走炮、斯图卡俯冲轰炸机
And infantry that just kept on coming.
还有不断涌进的步兵
- What's your name, Lieutenant? - George Rice, 10th Armor.
- 你叫什么名字 中尉? - 乔治莱斯 第10装甲师
- Good work, son. - You got any more mortar rounds, sir?
- 好样的! - 你们还有迫击炮弹吗 长官?
We're real short.
我们不够了
I'll try to make another ammo run if I can, but don't count on anything.
可以的话 我会再去拿一些 可别期望太高
Thank you, sir. I'll take this, Captain.
谢谢你! 这个我拿走 上尉
A panzer division's about to cut the road south.
一个德军装甲师要切断向南的道路
Looks like you guys are gonna be surrounded.
你们可能会被包围
We're paratroopers, Lieutenant. We're supposed to be surrounded.
我们是伞兵 中尉! 本来就该被包围的
- Good luck. - Thanks.
- 祝好运! - 谢谢!